AJITHKUMAR N

SUMMARY

As a forward-thinking sales person with 5+ years of experience and over \$8Crore+ in different sales products, I know firsthand the importance of empathy and attentiveness in closing a deal. Seeking a sales role where I can continue to foster and hone these traits as I continue to grow within an accomplished sales organization like **BYJU'S(Edu-Tech).**

EXPERIENCE

Senior Business Development Associate, 11/2022 - Current Byju's - Coimbatore, TAMIL NADU

- Oversaw maintenance of client notes on internal CRM system to facilitate future strategies and key results.
- Managed escalated client enquiries with exceptional professionalism and enthusiasm to maintain trust and reliability.
- Researched prospective clients to develop and execute cold call lists.

Business Development Executive, 03/2022 - 10/2022 Byju's - Tirunelveli

- Used software, databases scripts and tools during phone calls to support positive communications.
- Followed up with customers to offer additional support and check resolution satisfaction.
- Prepared reports and presentations detailing business development activities and outlining new initiatives.

Business Development Manager, 07/2017 - 08/2020 Chennai Star Furniture - Coimbatore

- Created short-term and long-term goals for business team to achieve objectives.
- Produced quotes and proposals to provide value and benefits to prospective clients.

Marketing & Business Development Associate, 06/2016 - 06/2017 Chennai Star Furniture - Coimbatore

- Handled credit and debit card payment processing to complete purchasing experience.
- Executed complete sales cycle process, from prospecting through to contract negotiations and closing.

EDUCATION

M.SC (APPLIED PSYCHOLOGY) - 54%, 2021 Bharathiyar University - Coimbatore, TN Co-organizer in TPSA TPAD OCT-10- 2020 & 21.

B.A ENGLISH Lit. - 61%, 2019
Government Arts College - Coimbatore, TN

HSC - 83%, 2016 St.Paul's Matric.Hr Sec School - Vellichandhai

SSLC - 98%, 2014 St.Paul's Matric.Hr Sec School - Vellichandhai [BHARAT SCOUT - RAJYA PURASKAR AWARD]



CONTACT

Address: Coimbatore, 641038

Phone: 7448608672

Email: akofficialuse@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Business planning and Development
- · Sales pipeline management
- Performance tracking and evaluations
- Relationship building and management
- Teamwork skills
- · Sales training & support
- Team building coordination
- · Objection handling
- Team leadership
- Relationship development
- Sales strategies
- Knowledge of Google Sheet
- · Knowledge of MS Office
- · Team management

LANGUAGES Tamil: C2 Proficient English: C1 Advanced

INTEREST

- · Business Ideas
- · Reading Books
- Psychological counselling
- · Carrom Board
- · Program Organizing